Cui Gongzi General Pei
Cui Gongzi General Pei
Visit the Chinese Valentine’s Day Lantern Festival
参观七夕元宵节
Make Yizhou Pengpi shine
让益州彭皮大放异彩
I am bold
我很大胆
Two of you please
请两位
Giving words to the Chinese Valentine’s Day wishing lantern
给七夕许愿灯寄语
請
请
Let’s write first
我们先写
Come and bring up the lamp
来把灯拿来
Good words
好话
Good meaning
好意
Okay, okay
好吧好吧
General Xiao Pei
萧培将军
Let’s write something real
让我们写一些真实的东西
Just write
直接写
Everyone marries a wife
人人都娶老婆
Bring them all
把它们全部带上
Let’s hold down the Western Army
镇压西军
They are all bachelors
他们都是单身汉
It’s like a bachelor’s army
这就像一支单身汉的军队
Not even granted this wish
甚至没有实现这个愿望
Good weather
天气好
Okay, okay
好吧好吧
Good
好
What if this is at Laolan Pass
如果这是在老兰关怎么办
Make such a fire
生这样的火
Must roast a lamb
一定要烤羊肉
Roasted until sizzling
烤至滋滋作响
Not to mention how fragrant
别提多香了
When I was little
小时候
Grandma also often
奶奶也经常
Inside the fire
火中
Give me roasted taro to eat
给我烤芋头吃
Next time
下次
I’ll bake it for you if I get the chance
如果有机会我会烤给你
It makes me a little hungry
这让我有点饿
Let’s take you to eat
带你去吃饭
This wonton tastes really good
这馄饨味道真好
Thank you, little lady
谢谢你，小女士
This is my homemade bone broth
这是我自制的骨头汤
So it tastes very good
所以味道很好
Store
商店
Business is good tonight
今晚生意不错
There aren’t many people around now
现在人不多
Everyone crowded to see
大家都挤着来看
Kill Han Li
杀死韩立
Beheading
斩首
The original one was killed
原来的那个被杀了
Awesome
太棒了
Where is Mr. Han in Yizhou City
韩先生在宜州市哪里
Kill him, kill him, kill him
杀了他，杀了他，杀了他
Master
大师
Everything has been arranged
一切都安排好了
The time is up
时间到了
Kill Han Li to sacrifice to the river god
杀韩立祭河神
The Savior
救世主
走
走
Two two persons
两个两个人
Take a look at our wristbands
看看我们的腕带
This is the finest buffalo leather
这是最好的水牛皮
My wife is a needle and a thread
我的妻子是一根针和一根线
sewn
缝制
Three layers of leather are particularly strong
三层皮革特别坚固
Master
大师
Are you an archer?
你是弓箭手吗？
It’s perfect to wear it
穿上它就完美了
Not bad
不错
Little Lady
小女士
Buy one for your husband
给你丈夫买一个
I fixed the windmill for you
我帮你修好了风车
Should you
你应该
Give me something
给我一些东西
He is not my husband
他不是我的丈夫
這
这
Obviously a good match
显然是一个很好的匹配
Am I wrong?
我错了吗？
Store
商店
What was that young man asking just now
刚才那个年轻人在问什么
Wrist guards
护腕
I asked but didn’t buy it
我问过但没有买
I don’t know what I’m thinking
我不知道自己在想什么
It seems that the emperor and his grandson have left no stone unturned
看来皇孙已千方百计
A big show has been arranged separately
单独安排了一场大秀
He Xiaowei, you praise me so much
何小伟，你太夸我了
I always feel like I have a plan
我总觉得我有一个计划
Not thorough enough
不够彻底
Laolan River Shibawan
老兰河十八湾
The first bay is the Silver Pine Beach
第一个海湾是银松海滩
Fish in Silver Pine Beach
银松海滩的鱼
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
十七郎十七郎
Ah Ying Shi Qi Lang Shi Qi Lang
Ah Ying Shi Qi Lang Shi Qi Lang
How to make it like this
如何做到这样
Nothing
什么都没有
Shichiro
七郎
How
如何
Kill what needs to be killed
杀死需要杀死的东西
Catch what needs to be caught
抓住需要抓住的东西
No one left behind
没有人掉队
對
对
Where are the things
东西在哪里
Lao Huang
老黄
Take it out
拿出来
I found the tiger talisman
我找到了老虎护身符
Right here
就在这里
These people
这些人
They are too stupid
他们太蠢了
I don’t even know how to lure a snake out of its hole
我什至不知道如何将蛇引出洞
It’s not that they are stupid
并不是他们傻
That’s because Shichiro is too smart
那是因为七郎太聪明了
Too stupid
太蠢了
Too smart
太聪明了
It’s not that something is missing
并不是缺少什么
Didn’t you put it in your arms
你不是把它放在怀里了吗
You just said you wanted to borrow the Tiger Talisman
你刚才说你想借虎符
Eliminate the murderous spirit
消除杀气
Look for where to put it
寻找放置位置
Is the dick here with you
这家伙在你身边吗
No
没有
Since you Cui Jiajun
自从你崔家骏
The mantis stalks the cicada and the oriole follows
螳螂捕蝉，黄雀尾随
No need to hide it
无需隐藏
Chen Xing
陈星
Tiger Talisman Tiger Talisman
虎符 虎符
You stole our tiger charm
你偷了我们的老虎符
Hurry up and hand over the Tiger Talisman
赶紧交出虎符
Take it and return it to us
拿走并归还给我们
You stole it
你偷了它
Little Lady
小女士
Aren’t you the emperor’s grandson’s concubine
你不是皇孙的妃子吗
Aren’t you going to elope with Shichiro?
你不打算和七郎私奔吗？
Although you are from the Cui family
虽然你是崔家的
But not in Cao Ying
但不在曹营
Is your heart in Han
你的心在汉吗
How to reverse it now
现在如何逆转
Help this pretty boy trick us
帮助这个漂亮男孩欺骗我们
Just make it clear
说清楚
What's going on
发生了什么事
Nonsense
废话
You two are having trouble
你们两个有麻烦了
It won’t be such a big fuss
不会有这么大的麻烦
Shut up
闭嘴
Li Huangsun
李皇孙
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
How to speak to my subordinates
如何与我的下属交谈
I am your concubine
我是你的小妾
How could you do this
你怎么能这样做
Let them insult my Cui Jiajun
让他们侮辱我崔家俊
She said it herself
她自己说的
She told us personally
她亲自告诉我们
Said she is the concubine of the emperor's grandson
说她是皇孙的妃子
I still want to follow us, Seventeen Lang
我还是想跟着我们十七郎
Elopement
私奔
How could she help?
她能提供什么帮助？
You pretty boy
你这个漂亮男孩
阿螢
阿萤
Master
大师
I was in danger at the mountain village
我在山村遇到危险
I just borrowed it
我刚刚借了它
The identity of the royal family members
王室成员的身份
These people don’t know what’s going on
这些人不知道发生了什么
This is such a misunderstanding
这真是一个误会
He Xiaowei
何小伟
Take a step to speak
迈出一步说话
Let's go
我们走吧
Don’t talk nonsense to him
别跟他废话
Master
大师
I'll be back soon
我很快就会回来
How did you guess it
你是怎么猜到的
Your people these days
现在你的人
I almost turned over the Korean mansion
我差点翻了韩国豪宅
I knew it
我就知道
Although you caught Han Li
虽然你抓住了韩立
But no tiger talisman was found
但没有找到虎符
So you don’t have to work hard
所以你不必努力工作
Sohu Talisman
搜狐护身符
Han Li is suspicious and cunning
韩立多疑狡猾
Since I didn’t carry it with me
因为我没有随身携带
Looking through the entire Han Mansion again
再看一遍整个韩府
Not found
未找到
Then he must have put it in
那么他一定把它放进去了
On my most trusted cronies
关于我最信任的密友
And you spread the news
你传播了这个消息
Pretend to kill Han Li again tonight
今晚再次假装杀掉韩立
To lure the remnants of Han Li
引诱韩立残部
Come out to save people
出来救人
This move of yours lures the snake out of its hole
你这一招引蛇出洞
Really good
真的很好
And you
还有你
Just keep an eye on me
请关注我
The mantis can catch the cicada
螳螂捕蝉
The oriole is behind
黄莺在后
That's right
没错
Then there is one more thing I don’t understand
还有一件事我不明白
Promise me
答应我
Invite to Chinese Valentine's Day
邀请参加七夕节
It’s to enjoy the lanterns with me
是和我一起赏花灯
To keep an eye on me personally
亲自关注我
To avoid
避免
I found out that you have a secret plan
我发现你有一个秘密计划
What about you
你呢
Ask me out
约我出去
What is it for
它有什么用
Come cruise with me
跟我一起巡游
Still don’t trust me
还是不相信我
Afraid that I might notice
担心我会注意到
It will ruin things for you
它会毁了你的事情
each other
彼此
Assignment
作业
Take a break
休息一下
The Empress thought of a way
皇后想到了一个办法
Let me leave the palace to practice Taoism
让我出宫修道
I will arrange for you to hang out
我会安排你出去玩
Inside the palace maid accompanying the monk
陪和尚的宫女内
Come out of the palace with me
跟我一起出宫吧
Don’t be afraid
别害怕
It should be just these days
应该是这几天
You can go out soon
你很快就可以出去
Someone is coming
有人来了
Take care when I leave
我走的时候请保重
Ajie
阿杰
The Governor has given the order
总督已下令
Let the female official beside Mrs. Xiao
让女官在肖夫人身边
As a stand-in
作为替身
I left the palace to practice Buddhism
我出宫修行
What
什么
Just let the female official out of the palace
就让女官出宫吧
What about that bitch Xiao
肖那个贱人呢
Still safe and sound
仍然安全无恙
You are angry with me in this palace
你在这座宫殿里生我的气
What's the matter with Sister?
姐姐怎么了？
Since the Governor has already
既然州长已经
Infatuated with Xiao
迷恋晓
Then we have to do it step by step
那我们就得一步一步来做
As the saying goes
俗话说
I can’t eat hot tofu in a hurry
我不能急着吃热豆腐
As long as we
只要我们
Put the wings around Xiao
把翅膀放在小肖身上
They were all cut off by her
都被她切断了
Are you still afraid that there is no way to kill her?
你还怕没办法杀掉她吗？
She is the late crown prince’s princess
她是已故王储的公主
Collude with rebels
与叛乱分子勾结
That's not
这不是
Obvious thing
显而易见的事情
Ajie
阿杰
This is Xiao
我是肖
Just a bitch
只是个婊子
Infatuate the Governor
让总督着迷
It’s only temporary
这只是暂时的
Since she is so domineering
既然她这么霸道
Then I will naturally find a way to kill her
那我自然会想办法杀掉她
Sister, don’t worry
姐姐，别担心
I will return to Luoyang immediately to supervise the battle
我将立即返回洛阳督战
As long as our Yuan family is in front of the battle
只要我们袁家在前线
Continue to make great contributions
继续做出巨大贡献
A sister is in Dadu
有个姐姐在大都
Place in mind
牢记
It’s impregnable
坚不可摧
Colonel
上校
This is my newly developed anesthetic
这是我新开发的麻醉剂
Already painted on the arrow
已经画在箭头上
You try
你试试
Let me see
让我看看
Miss
小姐
When the emperor and grandson rescued you
当皇孙救了你
Just take off your robe
脱掉你的长袍
Put it on you
戴在身上
That action is so cool
这个动作太酷了
I was stunned upstairs
楼上的我惊呆了
The emperor’s grandson promised us
皇孙答应我们的
Follow him
关注他
In the future
未来
No more worries
不再担心
Thanks to the emperor’s grandson
感谢皇孙
Miss, are you talking about the emperor’s grandson
小姐，您是说皇孙吗
Would you like this leather wristband
您想要这款皮革腕带
He will definitely like it
他一定会喜欢的
I only added a little bit of anesthetic
我只加了一点麻醉剂
Meet He Xiaowei
认识何小伟
Miss Gu is so polite
顾小姐很有礼貌
He Xiaowei’s smart outfit
何小伟的灵动装
You are so handsome and handsome
你好帅好帅
Miss
小姐
The emperor’s grandson asked us to wear men’s clothes
皇孙要求我们穿男装
Follow the army
跟随军队
I see Captain He’s outfit
我看到何队长的装扮
Very beautiful
非常漂亮
Miss, why don’t you ask Captain He for advice
小姐，要不请教一下何队长吧
Cut it as you like
随心所欲地剪下来
Talk
谈话
He Xiaowei is in the army
何小伟在部队
The courage gained through experience
通过经验获得的勇气
So heroic
如此英雄
Easy and good-looking
简单又好看
If I also wear this outfit
如果我也穿这套衣服
It’s just a painting of a tiger-like dog
这只是一幅像老​​虎一样的狗的画
No problem
没问题
My clothes
我的衣服
Taozi helped with the cooking
桃子帮忙做饭
You are not used to wearing men's clothing
你不习惯穿男装
Don’t know
不知道
They actually sleeve this place
他们实际上套住了这个地方
It’s very big
很大
And the shoulders and neck
还有肩膀和脖子
It’s also very generous
也很慷慨
Men's clothing bought on the market
市场上买的男装
Everything needs to be changed
一切都需要改变
Peach
桃子
Go back to the drawings we made
回到我们制作的图纸
Send it to Miss Gu’s room
发送到顾小姐房间
好
好
Thank you so much Captain He
非常感谢何队长
Miss Gu, you are welcome
顾小姐，不客气
Is this the dress
这是衣服吗
This is really a big deal
这确实是一件大事
Not easy to cut
不易切割
No
没有
This is the emperor's grandson
这是皇帝的孙子
Lend our lady’s clothes
借一下我们女士的衣服
Our lady washed it with her own hands
我们的女士亲手洗过它
I want to return it to the emperor’s grandson
我想还给皇孙
秋翠
秋翠
You talk too much
你说太多了
Actually
实际上
It was the emperor’s grandson who came to the rescue last time
上次救的是皇孙
I borrowed this coat
我借了这件外套
Cover for me
为我做掩护
He Xiaowei must not misunderstand
何小伟千万别误会
Where
哪里
Why did Miss Gu say this
顾小姐为何这么说
So
所以
I won’t delay Miss Gu
我不会耽误顾小姐
Colonel
上校
How do they talk
他们如何说话
Always taking some kind of detour
总是走某种弯路
Eighteen twists and turns
十八曲折
They are women in the boudoir
她们是闺中女子
Behave as you do
像你一样行事
Naturally euphemistic and subtle
自然委婉而微妙
Okay, stop watching the excitement
好吧，别再看热闹了
But they always mention the emperor’s grandson
但他们总是提到皇帝的孙子
But the emperor’s grandson is with us
但是皇帝的孙子和我们在一起
What does it matter
这有什么关系
What does it have to do with them
这和他们有什么关系
How do you know
你怎么知道
The emperor’s grandson has nothing to do with them
皇帝的孙子与他们无关
Young master takes a look
少爷看看
He is a person who is good at shooting
他是一个擅长射击的人
Put it on
穿上它
It couldn’t be more appropriate
再合适不过了
Not bad
不错
Little Lady
小女士
Buy one for your husband
给你丈夫买一个
I fixed the windmill for you
我帮你修好了风车
Should you
你应该
Give me something
给我一些东西
This Aying
这个艾因
It’s just a hard mouth but a soft heart
嘴硬心软
So beautiful
好漂亮
He Xiaowei
何小伟
I have something to tell you
我有话要告诉你
Some people are
有些人是
So hard-spoken and soft-hearted
嘴硬心软
I went out to work this morning
我今天早上出去工作了
Don’t let me know either
也不要让我知道
Really
真的
Obviously said not to send it
明明说不送
Finally gave it away
终于放弃了
Looks like the person who gave the wristband to the emperor’s grandson
看起来像是把腕带送给皇帝孙子的人
The emperor and his grandson must have attached great importance to it
皇帝和他的孙子一定非常重视
Of course
当然
It’s just my opinion
这只是我的意见
Although I value her
虽然我很重视她
But she
但是她
But she values ​​me more
但她更看重我
So
所以
It’s time to congratulate the emperor’s grandson
是时候恭喜皇孙了
What do you think
你觉得怎么样
The person who gave me the wristband
给我腕带的人
Compared to my concubine
与我的小妾相比
How
如何
Emperor Sun Shenyan
孙神言皇帝
I was trying to escape
我试图逃跑
Expedient measures
权宜措施
I just made this statement to deceive everyone
我发表此言论只是为了欺骗大家
I didn’t expect the emperor’s grandson
没想到是皇孙
His articulation is frivolous
他的表达很无聊
Publicly in front of my young master
当众在我少爷面前
Insult my reputation
侮辱我的名誉
I care so much about your son
我非常关心你的儿子
That's natural
这很自然
Why
为什么
It was not convenient for outsiders to know before
以前不方便外人知道
So I never told you
所以我从来没有告诉过你
Actually
实际上
I am the concubine of our young master
我是少爷的小妾
So please be careful when speaking
所以说话时请小心
Don’t do it again
不要再这样做
In front of my young master
在我少爷面前
Insulting my innocence
侮辱我的清白
Peach is gone
桃子不见了
Colonel
上校
Why did you tell the emperor?
你为什么要告诉皇帝？
You are the young master’s concubine
你是少爷的小妾
Today’s negotiations are reaching a critical point
今天的谈判已达到关键点
If you want to mess with him
如果你想惹他
Li Huangsun’s mind
李皇孙的心思
Must have one
必须有一个
Unexpected news is good
意外的消息是个好消息
You have to say this to disturb his mind
你必须这么说才能扰乱他的心
That’s not damaging
这不会造成损害
Does your daughter’s family have a good reputation?
你女儿家声誉好吗？
Between you and the young master
你和少爷之间
Innocent
无辜
Obviously not at all
显然根本不是
Not his concubine
不是他的妾
This is how you talk about yourself to outsiders
这就是你对外人谈论自己的方式
Do you want to get married in the future
你以后想结婚吗
Silly girl
傻姑娘
The man who can marry me in this world
这个世界上能娶我的男人
You don’t mind if I say that
你不介意我这么说
That’s not right
这是不对的
You always said before
你以前总是说
The man who can marry you in this world
这个世界上能娶你的男人
I'm afraid I haven't been born yet
恐怕我还没有出生
Why did you suddenly change your mind today
为什么今天突然改变主意
You finally discovered the world
你终于发现了这个世界
There is a man who can marry you
有一个男人可以嫁给你
Isn’t it
不是吗
Tell me who it is
告诉我他是谁
He is
他是
I won’t tell you
我不会告诉你
Let’s go quickly
我们快点走吧
Tell me
告诉我
I want to know
我想知道
Jianzhou defenders recognized talismans but not people
建州守军认符不认人
Our Cui Jiajun
我们的崔家俊
Now that the tiger talisman is in hand
虎符已到手
Jianzhou is already ours
建州已经是我们的了
Then you should take the Tiger Talisman
那你应该拿下虎符
Don’t think I don’t know
别以为我不知道
Don’t you just want Han Li
你不就是想要韩立吗
Enter the city with the Tiger Talisman
持虎符进城
Threaten Han Li
威胁韩立
In this way, there will be no need to waste a single soldier
这样一来，就不用浪费一兵一卒了
Capture Jianzhou City
攻克建州城
Yizhou City is already yours
益州城已经是你的了
What is the use of holding on to Han Li
留住韩立有什么用
Then you should steal the military rations
那你应该偷军粮
Give them all back to our Zhenxi Army
全部还给我镇西军
There should be a result today
今天应该有结果
I’m afraid it’s the grandson of the emperor
恐怕是皇帝的孙子
Not that easy to talk to
不太容易交谈
Han Li
韩立
I want to order
我要订购
Master
大师
Your hair is loose
你的头发松了
Let me help you comb it
我帮你梳理一下
好
好
Shichiro
七郎
Actually about
实际上大约
He Xiaowei of Cui Jiajun
He Xiaowei of Cui Jiajun
There is a saying
有一句话
I don’t know whether to say it or not
我不知道该不该说
Improper
不当
好
好
Our young master said it
我们少爷说的
We have been talking for several days
我们已经聊了好几天了
According to the old covenant
根据旧约
This Han Li was captured by the Zhenxi Army
这个韩立被镇西军俘虏了
Nayizhou City
那一州市
It will be owned by Zhenxi Army
它将归镇西军所有
But this is the tiger symbol
但这是老虎符号
Acquired by our Cui Jiajun
被我们崔家俊收购了
This is Jianzhou City
这里是建州市
It should belong to our Cui family army
应该是我们崔家军的
The tiger talisman is obviously us
老虎符显然是我们
Found first
首先找到
You took it away by trickery
你用诡计把它拿走了
And Yizhou City
还有宜州市
Obviously it belongs to our Zhenxi Army
显然是我们镇西军的
You entered the city first
你先进入城市
Steal food and grass
偷食物和草
Return the food and grass first
先把粮草还回去
Let’s talk about Jianzhou
我们来谈谈建州
This is it
就是这样
It’s better for everyone to stay calm
每个人都保持冷静比较好
Discuss it carefully
仔细讨论
Speaking is better than singing
说胜于唱
What discussion
什么讨论
That’s what you want
这就是你想要的
Take advantage of our Zhenxi Army
趁我镇西军有利
This warrior
这个战士
You can’t say that
你不能这么说
Since it is a discussion
既然是讨论
Then give in at a loss
然后茫然屈服
Our Cui Jiajun
我们的崔家俊
Everything is possible
一切皆有可能
行
行
Then tell me
然后告诉我
How do you plan to suffer a loss
您打算如何遭受损失
His Royal Highness Didn’t Want to
殿下不想
Help the country to fall
帮助国家陷落
Recover the Eastern and Western Capitals
收复东西都
You can suppress the Western Army
你可以镇压西军
Current grain storage
当前粮食库存
Don’t talk about recovering both the east and west
不要谈恢复东西方
I’m afraid it’s even the edge of the Luo River
恐怕连洛河边了
Can’t even touch it
连碰都碰不到
If you are in Yizhou
如果你在宜州
Delay for a few more days
再延迟几天
I'm afraid this food reserve will become increasingly insufficient
这个粮食储备恐怕会越来越不够了
Now you and I have two armies
现在你和我有两支军队
On the issue of statehood
关于建国问题
Always arguing
总是争论
But follow the rules
但要遵守规则
This Tiger Talisman
此虎符
Since already
既然已经
Acquired by our Cui Jiajun
被我们崔家俊收购了
Then Jianzhou City
当时的建州市
It should belong to our Cui family army
应该是我们崔家军的
It’s just that we want to ask Han Li
只是想问问韩立
For convenience
为了方便
So our young master
所以我们的少爷
I just said
我刚刚说了
We plan to suffer some losses
我们计划遭受一些损失
I will give you fifty carts of food and grass
给你五十车粮草
This can also help you
这也可以帮助你
Leave camp and head to Luoyang as soon as possible
尽快离开营地，前往洛阳
With the bravery of your army
凭借你军队的勇敢
Are you still afraid that you won’t be able to defeat Luoyang?
还怕打不过洛阳吗？
That’s what you said
这就是你说的
Feel like we
感觉像我们
Got a big deal
有一件大事
Fifty carts of grain and grass
粮草五十车
A mere fifty loads of grain and grass
区区五十担粮草
Only enough for us to suppress the Western Army
只够我们镇压西军
Two meals a day
一日两餐
Reluctantly arrived at the bank of Luo River
恋恋不舍地来到洛河畔
Which one is more important, Jianzhou or Luoyang
建州和洛阳哪个更重要
His Royal Highness the Imperial Sun
太阳殿下
You can’t tell the difference
你无法分辨出差异
Natural
自然
Would the emperor be willing to use Han Li
皇帝愿意使用韩立吗
In exchange for fifty loads of food and grass
换取五十担粮草
Yes
是的
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
十七郎十七郎
好
好
His Royal Highness the Imperial Sun
太阳殿下
Nature is a promise
自然是一个承诺
As long as you take Han Li down
只要打倒韩立
Leave it to us Cui Jiajun
交给我们崔家军
Then our young master
那么我们的少爷
I will never break my promise
我永远不会违背我的诺言
Food and grass will be delivered on time
食物和草将按时交付
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
十七郎十七郎
These fifty cars are too few
这五十辆车太少了
Old Bao
老包
Please leave me alone
请别打扰我
Tell me
告诉我
What's the plan
计划是什么
What kind of plan
什么样的计划
Didn’t you agree on purpose
你不是故意同意的吗
That Captain He
那个何队长
Exchange Han Li for fifty carts of grain and grass
用韩立换五十车粮草
Are you planning to kill three birds with one stone
你打算一石三鸟吗
Taking advantage of the Cui family's unpreparedness
趁崔家不备
Capture Liangcao and Han Li together
联手擒拿良草和韩立
By the way, capture Jianzhou again
对了，再攻克建州
Han Li has both grain and grass
韩立粮草兼备
And win Jianzhou
并赢得建州
Is there any good way
有什么好的办法吗
Not now
现在不行
You are confident
你有信心
Has it been planned in advance
是否已提前计划
Why don't you
你为什么不呢
I agreed so easily
我这么轻易就同意了
That Captain He
那个何队长
Such harsh conditions
如此恶劣的条件
I have a friend
我有一个朋友
My friend
我的朋友
He fell in love with a girl
他爱上了一个女孩
Wait until the Zhenxi Army hands over Han Li
等到镇西军交出韩立
Ask Zuo Ying to take Han Li and Tiger Talisman
让左影拿走韩立和虎符
Leave camp immediately
立即离开营地
Go to recover Jianzhou
去收复建州
I'd better go there myself
我最好自己去那里
No need
不需要
Now we have Han Li and Tiger Talisman
现在有了韩立和虎符
Jianzhou City must be easily captured
建州城必须轻松攻克
Now in Luoyang instead
现在在洛阳
That’s the toughest part
这是最困难的部分
I guess Li Ni
我猜是李妮
After getting the food and grass
获得食物和草后
It will definitely point directly at Luoyang
肯定会直指洛阳
We must be the first to do so
我们必须成为第一个这样做的人
His front
他的正面
What about your friend
你的朋友呢
He is from our Zhenxi Army
他是我们镇西军的
I am still an old acquaintance of yours in Beijing
我还是你在北京的老熟人
Why are you shaking your head
你为什么摇头
Say it
说出来
This girl
这个女孩
He shouldn't like it
他不应该喜欢
Shouldn’t like
不应该喜欢
Did he fall in love
他恋爱了吗
The Drunk Man in the Red Mansion
红楼醉汉
In fact, it doesn’t matter
其实这并不重要
As long as this poor man
只要这个可怜的人
Good character
性格好
It doesn’t matter
没关系
No
没有
What are you talking about
你在说什么
He finally fell in love with someone
他终于爱上一个人了
But that girl
但是那个女孩
Already someone else’s concubine
已经是别人的妾了
Seventeen Lang, Seventeen Lang
十七郎，十七郎
I finally understand
我终于明白了
You are so unusual today
你今天很不寻常
Because of this
因为这个
What is so abnormal
有什么异常
What's wrong with me
我怎么了
I’m talking about that friend
我正在谈论那个朋友
行
行
Let’s do it today
今天就开始吧
Tell me about your friend
告诉我关于你朋友的事
National crisis is now at hand
国家危机即将来临
He still thinks about little things about love
他仍然想着爱情的小事
He informed you of this
他通知了你这件事
It shows that he is deeply worried
这表明他很担心
I will definitely continue to pester you in the future
以后我一定会继续缠着你
Not really
不是真的
Okay
好的
He knew that this man had a husband
他知道这个男人有一个丈夫
Also secretly coveting
也暗自觊觎
Seventeen Lang, let me tell you
十七郎，我告诉你
Color makes the mind faint
颜色使头脑昏厥
Actually
实际上
You don’t need to say anything
你不需要说什么
Shichiro
七郎
I advise you to hurry up
我建议你快点
Break it off with your friend
与你的朋友分手
Otherwise you are not afraid of being black if you are close to the ink
不然近墨不怕被黑
One day you will also like it
有一天你也会喜欢它
Someone else’s concubine
别人的妾
Shichiro
七郎
Think twice
三思而后行
Today Li Huangsun
今天李皇孙
So lost
迷失了
You agreed to us so easily
你这么轻易就同意了我们
I don’t know what happened
我不知道发生了什么
Who knows
谁知道
Then I will let Chen Xing
那我就让晨星
Going to arrange food and grass
去安排粮草
Wait
等等
I thought of another plan
我想到了另一个计划
If the time comes
如果时机成熟
Their people
他们的人
Arrived in Luoyang before us
先于我们到达洛阳
We ambush again
我们再次伏击
Then we can
然后我们就可以
The slave goes out of the palace to practice Taoism for the empress
奴才出宫为皇后修道
It is the slave’s blessing
这是奴隶的祝福
I am just a slave who has been serving the queen since childhood
我只是一个从小侍奉女王的奴隶
From the mansion
从豪宅
To the palace
前往宫殿
So many years
这么多年了
The slave is reluctant to leave
奴隶不愿离开
Empress’ future
皇后的未来
Take care
保重
Practice is a good thing
多练习是好事
Gather blessings for me
为我收集祝福
Gather blessings for yourself
为自己收集祝福
I still have Jin Niang by my side
我身边还有锦娘
Don’t worry
别担心
It’s you
是你
Take care of yourself
照顾好自己
Take care of Mrs. Jiang for me too
也替我照顾一下江太太
Go ahead
继续
是
是
Your Majesty, don’t worry
陛下，别担心
The slave is gone
奴隶不见了
Grand Governor
总督
It’s all done
一切都完成了
好
好
Go and talk to the lady
去和那位女士说话
Just say
就说
I have taken it out on her behalf
我已代她取出
Where is Concubine Xiao
萧妃在哪里
In case you find out
如果你发现
She is a smart person
她是一个聪明人
I will definitely think
我一定会想
It was sent by Zheng Guogong
郑国公发来的
Kill those palace maids
杀死那些宫女
Taking vent to Mrs. Wei
向魏太太发泄
But just in case Concubine Xiao can’t think about it
不过以防万一萧妃想不出来
Refused to give up and got into a fight
拒绝放弃并陷入战斗
Wouldn’t it be detrimental to Zheng Guogong
这岂不是对郑国公不利
Just a few slaves
只有几个奴隶
Kill, just kill
杀，就杀
I said it too
我也说过
She is a smart person
她是一个聪明人
She won’t do it because of them
因为他们，她不会这么做
Ignorance
无知
Strike an egg against a stone
以卵击石
Emperor Sun Wei’s visit at night
孙威皇帝夜访
Do you want to be a gentleman
你想成为绅士吗
What are you here for?
你来这里做什么？
I'm coming today
我今天来
I want to pay you back
我想还钱给你
What else can you give me
你还能给我什么
I came here to explain to you
我来这里是为了向你解释
I misunderstood during the day
白天我误会了
I thought the wristband was a gift from you
我以为腕带是你送给我的礼物
The words are offensive
这些话令人反感
Please forgive me
请原谅我
You thought it was from me
你以为这是我写的
是
是
I found out later
后来才知道
It was a gift from Miss Gu
这是顾小姐送的礼物
But I have already removed the wrist guards
但是我已经取下了护腕
Give it back to her
还给她
You thought it was from me
你以为这是我写的
So I like wearing it
所以我喜欢戴它
Later I discovered
后来我发现
It was a gift from Miss Gu
这是顾小姐送的礼物
Give it back to her
还给她
You want to tell me this
你想告诉我这个
That's true
确实如此
Not really
不是真的
This is not what I am
这不是我
Isn’t it just right for me to see the moonlight
我看月光不是正好吗
Perfect for grabbing the Tiger Talisman
非常适合抓住老虎护身符
You guessed wrong this time
这次你猜错了
The Tiger Talisman is not here
虎符不在
I know
我知道
Since you know
既然你知道了
Why are you still here
你为什么还在这里
我
我
This is not what I am
这不是我
Colonel
上校
Are you asleep
你睡了吗
I'm ready to sleep
我准备睡觉了
Then I’ll go to sleep too
那我也去睡觉
Okay, go quickly
好的，快点
Then take a rest early, Captain
那就早点休息吧，队长
Got it
知道了
Why are you covering your eyes
你为什么捂住眼睛
My face is so red
我的脸好红
My wife, it’s hot here
我的妻子，这里很热
It's windy and cold tonight
今晚风很大，很冷
The emperor’s grandson actually feels too hot
皇孙实在太热了
You just
你只是
Why do you need to cover it up for me
你为什么要为我掩盖
Trespassing into the woman’s bedroom late at night
深夜闯入女方卧室
The emperor and his grandson don’t mind the melon fields and plum blossoms
皇孙不介意瓜田梅花
I still dislike it
我还是不喜欢它
Let me tell you something serious
让我告诉你一些严肃的事情
Today you use fifty carts of grain and grass
今天你用了五十车粮草
It is obviously unfair to exchange for statehood
以换取国家地位显然是不公平的
I know your Cui family
我认识你们崔家
Manpower is lurking in Beijing
人才潜伏在北京
My father was detained in Beijing by Sun Jing
我父亲在北京被孙静拘留
I would like to lend you a hand
我想帮你一把
Rescue my father
救救我的父亲
The emperor is so rude
皇帝太粗鲁了
What if I don’t agree
如果我不同意怎么办
If you don’t agree
如果您不同意
Then I will
那我就
阿螢
阿萤
Are you asleep
你睡了吗
I just fell asleep
我刚刚睡着了
I have something important to discuss with you
我有重要的事情要和你讨论
Okay, here I come
好的，我来了
Master
大师
Did the military newspaper come from somewhere?
军事报纸是从什么地方来的吗？
Actually, it’s nothing important
其实这并不重要
It’s just what I heard from Taozi
这只是我从桃子那里听到的
You haven’t had dinner
你还没吃晚饭
That’s why I came to see you
这就是我来看你的原因
But I see your complexion
但我看到你的肤色
Pretty good
相当不错
It seems that I am worrying too much
看来是我多虑了
But I had more snacks in the afternoon
但是我下午吃了更多零食
I have no appetite at night
我晚上没胃口
Then go to bed early
那就早点睡觉
Young master, please rest early
少爷早点休息
I’ve found out everything
我已经发现了一切
The ashes of Mrs. Shen and Mrs. Jiang
沉夫人、姜夫人的骨灰
They were all thrown outside the city
他们都被扔到了城外
Look at her following me for a while
看看她跟着我一会儿
But ended up with one
但最终得到了一个
The end of a broken life
破碎生活的结束
Empress
皇后
Cry if you want to
想哭就哭
I won’t cry
我不会哭
Being a Crown Princess
成为太子妃
I have to be strong and stop crying
我必须坚强，停止哭泣
But I hate myself
但我讨厌自己
Why is it so useless
为什么这么没用
Failed to save Jiang’s belly
没能拯救江氏的肚子
The prince’s flesh and blood
王子的骨肉
If one day I go underground
如果有一天我转入地下
The prince will never forgive me
王子永远不会原谅我
Empress
皇后
The grandson is still alive
孙子还活着
If it weren’t for you
如果没有你
He won’t even survive now
他现在甚至无法生存
He is still waiting for you, Madam
他还在等你，女士
I know
我知道
For the grandson
为了孙子
I also want to live well
我也想活得好
The slave knows
奴隶知道
The Empress bears the humiliation
皇后忍辱负重
For what
为了什么
Mother Shen also knows
沉妈妈也知道
Tell the slave before she left
在奴隶离开前告诉她
She followed her empress to death without regret
她无怨无悔地追随皇后而死
Jin Niang too
锦娘也是
Just a word from the queen
女王一句话
Jin Niang died immediately
锦娘当场就死了
Also happy
也很高兴
Death without regrets
死无悔
Empress
皇后
Don’t talk about death easily
不要轻易谈论死亡
Death is the easiest
死亡是最容易的
When the Prince passed away
王子去世时
If I take a knife and touch my neck
如果我拿刀摸我的脖子
That’s the easiest
这是最简单的
The world will still praise me for my steadfastness
世界仍然会称赞我的坚定
But I understand in my heart
但我心里明白
I can't do that
我做不到
I have to survive
我必须生存
I want to do well
我想做得好
Dealing with Sun Jing
对付孙静
Maybe I can still find a chance
也许我还能找到机会
Keep your grandson
留下你的孙子
I can still find opportunities to act by ear
我仍然可以找到见机行事的机会
Help me recover the Dayu Dynasty
帮我恢复大禹王朝
The empress feels bitter
皇后心里苦涩
All slaves understand
所有奴隶都明白
You said
你说
This child Xuanze
轩泽这孩子
Have you grown taller again
你又长高了吗
Han Chang took him to hide in Tibet
韩畅带他躲进西藏
I don’t know about tonight either
我也不知道今晚会怎样
Can you eat enough
你能吃饱吗
Can you have a good sleep
你能睡个好觉吗
Your Highness
殿下
Have a drink of water
喝点水
General Han
韩将军
Didn’t we discuss this before
我们之前不是讨论过这个
Are you traveling disguised as your uncle or nephew?
您是否伪装成叔叔或侄子旅行？
General, just call me Aze
将军，叫我阿泽就可以了
The grandson’s identity is different
孙子身份不同
No one is around here
这里没人
Etiquette to be observed
应遵守的礼仪
You should still keep it
你仍然应该保留它
Are you hungry, Your Highness?
殿下您饿了吗？
Not hungry
不饿
General Han
韩将军
Has there been any news from the concubine
妃子有什么消息
No
没有
來
来
The Crown Princess has a strong heart
太子妃有一颗坚强的心
Endure the humiliation
忍辱​​负重
If it weren’t for her clever arrangement
如果不是她的巧妙安排
My grandson and I
我和我的孙子
It’s hard to escape Sun Jing’s arrest
孙静抓捕难逃
It’s a long journey now
现在是一个漫长的旅程
Intermittent news from the Crown Princess
来自太子妃的断断续续的消息
This is also common
这也很常见
I hope my mother and concubine will be safe and sound
愿我的母妃平安无事
Met the emperor’s grandson
见到了皇帝的孙子
I don’t know why the emperor and grandson invited him
不知道皇孙为何请他
Together in this Yizhou City
一起在这个宜州城
Military Disturbance
军事骚乱
I haven’t had a word with the young master yet
我还没和少爷说过一句话
I prepared some wine today
我今天准备了一些酒
I would like to treat you to a few drinks
我想请你喝几杯
I never drink alcohol
我从不喝酒
I have something to ask for
我有事要问
Please give me some thin noodles, sir
请给我一些细面条，先生
The emperor’s grandson is in trouble
皇帝的孙子有麻烦了
Just say it
直接说
I didn’t know Captain He’s identity before
我之前并不知道何队长的身份
If any offense
如有任何冒犯
I hope you will forgive me
希望你能原谅我
What identity
什么身份
Her identity
她的身份
Master
大师
Why ask even though you already know
即使你已经知道为什么还要问
She is no more than our military captain
她只不过是我们的军事队长
What identity can it have
它可以有什么身份
Young master, you don’t have to hide
少爷，你不用隐藏
I already know everything
我已经知道一切
As long as the young master agrees
只要少爷同意
Do me this favor
帮我个忙
I will keep this secret
我会保守这个秘密
Never let others know
永远不要让别人知道
Don’t worry, sir
别担心，先生
I, Li Shiqi, have said it all
我郦食其都说了
A horse is hard to catch
马难追
As long as the young master agrees
只要少爷同意
I will keep this a secret
我会保守秘密
Rotten in the stomach
烂在胃里
You don’t want to kill me to silence me
你不想杀了我来让我沉默
Master
大师
Although your Cui family army is powerful
你们崔家军队虽然强大
But our Zhenxi Army is also in Yizhou
可是我们镇西军也在益州
Can the young master succeed
少爷能否成功
The emperor and his grandson were joking
皇帝和他的孙子在开玩笑
Everyone is the master of diligence
人人都是勤奋大师
The emperor and grandson tell me
皇孙告诉我
What's the matter with you
你怎么了
Need help from our Cui family
需要我们崔家的帮助
But it doesn’t matter
但这并不重要
My father, King Liang
我的父亲梁王
Detained in Beijing by Sun Jing
孙静在北京被拘留
I know your Cui family
我认识你们崔家
There are experts lurking in Beijing
北京潜伏着专家
As long as the young master can help me
只要少爷能帮我
I will be able to rescue my father
我一定能救出我的父亲
Master
大师
The captain asked
队长问
Just know
只要知道
You are coming to the emperor’s grandson
你来找皇孙了
It’s time for you to go back and take your medicine
你该回去吃药了
I say Shikiro
我说四郎
You don’t say
你不说
Are we going to have a Hongmen Banquet today
今天我们要办鸿门宴吗
Why is it finished so quickly
为什么这么快就完结了
You said
你说
This Mr. Cui
这位崔先生
What kind of person is he?
他是一个什么样的人？
Looking polite
看起来很有礼貌
Like a young man
像个年轻人
It really doesn’t look like it
看起来确实不像
A person who can lead troops to fight
能带兵打仗的人
Yeah
是的
He is such a person
他就是这样的人
A quiet and weak person
一个安静而软弱的人
You can actually get here from Yingzhou
其实你可以从瀛州到达这里
Conquered so many cities
征服了如此多的城市
Do you think this is strange
你觉得这很奇怪
Cui Yi’s son
崔毅的儿子
It shouldn’t be bad
应该不会太差
Who is Cui Yina
崔伊娜是谁
The famous general of the day
当今著名将军
With General Sun Jingpei
与孙敬佩将军
Earlier they were also known as the Three Heroes of the Kingdom
早些时候他们也被称为王国三英雄
Then tell me
然后告诉我
What kind of person is He Xiaowei
何小伟是一个什么样的人
This
这个
I really can’t see through this
我实在是看不透
You know
你知道
I have been fighting in the battlefield for more than ten years
我在战场上征战了十几年
What kind of person have I never seen
我没见过什么样的人
But such a person
但是这样的人
I’ve never seen it before
我以前从未见过
You said she is a woman
你说她是女人
She is cruel and quick
她残忍而敏捷
Extremely resourceful
足智多谋
I really can’t figure it out
我实在想不通
So I always feel
所以我总觉得
This Captain He’s identity is not simple
这个何队长身份不简单
Every word she said
她说的每一句话
I don’t know how much I can believe it
我不知道我能相信多少
Right
右
Shichiro
七郎
The army is ready to march
军队已做好行军准备
Our defense in Yizhou
我们在益州的防守
Also prepared
也准备好了
When are you leaving
你什么时候走
The sooner the better
越早越好
Colonel
上校
When I rush there
当我冲到那里时
The young master looks very ugly
少爷长得很丑
No problem
没问题
The young master has already told what Li Ni said
李妮的话少爷已经说了
Tell me everything
告诉我一切
Li Yi is a killer
李毅是杀手
He actually said blackmail
他实际上说的是勒索
Want to kill two birds with one stone
想一石二鸟
I want to deceive my true identity
我想欺骗我的真实身份
I want to trick the young master into agreeing to him again
我又想骗小少爷答应他
Rescue King Liang
营救梁王
Fortunately, the young master was not fooled
还好少爷没上当
But this is Li Ni
但这是李妮
Already starting to get suspicious
已经开始怀疑
Fortunately, you have persuaded the young master
还好你说服了少爷
Start the Chen Bing Luo River early
早起陈兵洛河
What's here
这里是什么
Let me clean up first
我先清理一下
Colonel
上校
Shall we take this windmill with us
我们可以带着这个风车吗
Throw it away
扔掉它
Really threw it away
真的把它扔掉了